About

33 years old Zwanenveld 9150 6538 SJ NIJMEGEN THE NETHERLANDS **1** (+31) 6 30607282 ■ benoit@viguier.nl ★ viguier.nl in beviguier **y** @ildyria ☐ ildyria

Language

French ****

English ★★★★

German ★★★★★

Spanish **** Japanese ★★★★

OS Preference

Debian ★★★★★ WSL **★★★★**★

MacOs ★★★★ Windows ★★★★

Dutch ★★★★★

Benoît Viguier

PhD. · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I defended my PhD thesis on December 13^{th} , 2021. I am passionate about symmetric cryptography, formal methods, and beautiful code. I am also a competitive ballroom dancer and a photographer.

Education

PhD in Cryptography & Formal Methods

Nijmegen, The Netherlands RADBOUD UNIVERSITEIT

Software Engineer

INSA (NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF APPLIED SCIENCES)

MRes. in Computer Science UNIVERSITY RENNES 1

MSc. in Mathematics

UNIVERSITY RENNES 1

Sept. 2016 - Dec. 2021 Rennes, France Sept. 2014 - 2016 Rennes. France Sept. 2015 - 2016 Rennes, France

Sept. 2006 - 2011

Skills___

Programming C/C++, Coq, Java, Python, RISC-V asm, ARM Asm, PHP, LTFX **Dev. Env.** Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA, Clion, PhpStorm, Git, Atom

Experience _____

Information Security Expert - DevOps Eng. Crypto.

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

• Designing and implementing the Registration Authority of a Public Key Infrastructure

Java, PKI, Scrum

Activities

Ballroom Dancing Photography Piano Rock climbing **Martial Arts** Sailing

PhD Candidate

RADBOUD UNIVERSITY

- · Designing symmetric cryptography algorithm.
- · Writting optimized implementation for lightweight schemes.
- Using formal methods to verify cryptographic C implementations.

Cog, Formal Approaches, Cryptanalysis, C, Assembly

Internship: Software Engineer & Researcher

STMICROELECTRONICS

- Verification of the truncated tree search using Formal Methods.
- Application to differential and linear trail search.

Coq, C++, Differential Cryptanalysis, Hash functions

Internship: Software Engineer

MISSION CRITICAL IT • SNOMED CT, ICD10PCS and NLP parsing.

Lucene, OpenNLP, Stanford Parser, SWRL, Ontologies, JAVA

· Junior Highschool and Highschool

Mathematics Teacher

Teamwork, teaching skills, formalism

Nijmegen, The Netherlands

Sep. 2016 - Feb. 2021

Apr. 2021 - current

Brussels, Belgium

Feb. - Jun. 2016

Brussels, Belgium

Jun. - Sep. 2015

2011 - 2014

Publications

A Panorama on Classical Cryptography

Nijmegen, The Netherlands

PHD THESIS Dec. 2021

Designing, Implementing, Breaking, Verifying, and Standardizing Cryptography

In this thesis we cover a large part of the classical cryptography world: we examine the design of new symmetric
primitive; we explore implementation strategies of lightweight schemes; we analyze a new high performance algorithm; we use formal verification to prove the correctness of Elliptic Curve Cryptography implementations; and
finally we describe one of the way algorithms are standardized.

A Coq proof of the correctness of X25519 in TweetNaCl

Dubrovnik, Croatia

34TH IEEE COMPUTER SECURITY FOUNDATIONS SYMPOSIUM

Jun. 2021

• We formally prove that the C implementation of the X25519 key-exchange protocol in the TweetNaCl library correctly implements the protocol from Bernstein's 2006 paper, as standardized in RFC 7748, as well as the absence of undefined behavior. We also formally prove that X25519 is mathematically correct, i.e., that it correctly computes scalar multiplica- tion on the elliptic curve Curve25519. The proofs are all computer-verified using Coq.

Assembly or Optimized C for Lightweight Cryptography on RISC-V?

Vienna, Austria

CRYPTOLOGY AND NETWORK SECURITY

Dec 2020

• In this work, we studied the general impact of optimizing symmetric-key algorithms in assembly and in plain C on RISC-V architectures. Additionally, we present optimized implementations of NIST's lightweight candidates, with speed-ups of up to 81% over available implementations, and discuss general implementation strategies.

Cryptanalysis of MORUS

Brisbane, Australia

ADVANCES IN CRYPTOLOGY - ASIACRYPT 2018, LNCS

Dec. 2018

• We present a linear correlation in the keystream of full MORUS, which can be used to distinguish its output from random and to recover some plaintext bits in the broadcast setting.

KangarooTwelve: fast hashing based on Keccak-p

Leuven, Belgium

APPLIED CRYPTOGRAPHY AND NETWORK SECURITY - ACNS 2018, LNCS

July 2018

 KangarooTwelve, a fast and secure arbitrary output-length hash function aiming at a higher speed than the FIPS 202's SHA-3 and SHAKE functions.

Gimli: A Cross-Platform Permutation

Taipei, Taiwan

CRYPTOGRAPHIC HARDWARE AND EMBEDDED SYSTEMS - CHES 2017, LNCS

Sept. 2017

 Gimli, a 384-bit permutation designed to achieve high security with high performance across a broad range of platforms.

Extra Activities

Standard Ballroom & Formation Dancer

The Netherlands
Mar. 2018 - PRESENT

MEMBER OF DSV SWAY OF LIFE

- 2021 2^{nd} place Dutch Championship in couple C-class Standard Dalfsen
- + 2021 $\mathbf{1}^{st}$ place Dutch Championship in Formation Dancing Rotterdam
- + 2020 $\mathbf{4}^{th}$ place Dutch Championship in couple C-class Standard Dalfsen
- * 2019 $\mathbf{1}^{st}$ place Dutch Championship in Formation Dancing Almere
- 2019 Finalist World Championship in Formation Dancing Moskow
 2018 1st place Dutch Championship in Formation Dancing Almere

Landscapes & Ballroom Photography

The Netherlands

PHOTOGRAPHER

Jul. 2018 - PRESENT

- Landscapes & long exposures
- Ballroom Photography WDSF, NADB, NTDS, ETDS
- Events PhD Defenses
- Portraiture

LycheeOrg The Netherlands

Main Developer & Administrator

Aug. 2018 - PRESENT

• Complete rewrite of the Lychee image server with Laravel.